It's almost morning.
We should've found a town by now.
This is the way the woodsman told us to go, right?
Have you listened to anything I've been saying?
For the last couple hours, I've been saying...
Well, that settles it.
I'm gonna walk up ten feet ahead of you.
- Help!
- Huh?
I'm stuck!
I hear something!
It's probably nothing.
Hey, look.
"Pottsfield, 1 mile."
A town! Let's go this way.
Okay, let's go this way.
Not... ugh.
Hello?
- Hey, you.
- Who? Me?
- Yeah, you.
- Oh.
Hello.
It's you again. I'm stuck.
Help me out of here, and I'll owe you a favor.
Whoa! I get a wish?
No, no, no. Not a wish.
I'm not magical.
I'll just do you a good turn.
Can you turn me into a tiger?
Um, no. I just said I'm not magical.
It doesn't have to be a magical tiger.
Greg, stop talking to a bush.
- Okay.
- Huh?
Thanks. I owe you a favor.
So, um...
you two are lost kids with no purpose in life, right?
Uh-huh.
How about I bring you to Adelaide of the pasture,
the good woman of the woods?
She could help you get home.
Oh.
N-No, no. No, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Magic talking birds leading us to fairy godmothers
in the mysterious...
I'm going to Pottsfield.
Yeah, we're going to Pottsfield.
Come on!
What about the favor?
I'll think of my wish later.
Ohh.
So, let's small-talk.
My name's Greg. What's yours?
Beatrice.
My brother's name is Wirt.
Who cares?
And my frog's name is Wirt Jr.
but that may change.
Okay, that's great.
How about you and I ditch your brother?
Mm. Maybe later.
So, is it nice being a bird?
- Nope.
- Oh.
Do you like waffles?
No, waffles make me sick.
I eat... m-maggots.
- Ahh!
- What?!
How can you not eat waffles?!
- Ahh!
- What?
I stepped on a pumpkin!
Aha!
Civilization, see?
Now...
Huh? What the...
All right. Let's rejoin society.
Hello? Hello?
Hm,
see anybody?
No...
Oh, I see you.
Yeah, I see you, too, Greg.
Hey, not to be obnoxious, but an abandoned ghost town
doesn't seem like it's gonna be that useful getting you guys home.
There's got to be somebody...
somewhere.
Excuse me?
Anyone here?
Hello?
Oh. Sorry.
Uh,
I'm looking for a phone.
Um, I'm sorry.
Did you find anything?
Nope. Where's Greg?
Do you hear that?
Huh?
♪ ...let spirits meet ♪
♪ around the barn of Pottsfield town ♪
- Hmm?
- Huh?
♪ O hie thee forth o'er golden mead ♪
♪ Yon is the maypole set  ♪
♪ A ribbon to wind thy soul ♪
♪ And to bind love to thy breast ♪
What the...
Oh, pardon me there.
Say, you folks ought to don your vegetables
and celebrate the harvest with us.
Uh...
Oh! You're wearing costumes.
Well, sure. Pumpkins can't move on their own... can they?
Ha. No. Yeah, no.
Good thing I didn't take this off.
You guys find this place as creepy as I do, right?
So it's some kind of weird cult
where they wear vegetable costumes
and dance around a big thing.
They seem nice enough.
Okay, you're in denial. That's fine.
But I'm just saying, something feels off about this place.
Well,
maybe I can find someone here who will give us a ride home.
Greg, you stay out of trouble.
Beatrice, thank you, but you can leave.
I can't leave.
I'm honor-bound to help you
since you guys helped me.
That's the bluebird rules.
Uh, okay.
Beatrice, would you care for this dance?
No thanks.
No thanks, no thanks. I said no thank you.
Say, aren't you a little too... early?
What do you mean?
I mean it doesn't seem like you're ready to join us just yet.
Join you? Yeah, no, I'm just passing through.
Folks don't tend to "pass through" Pottsfield.
Oh... Yeah?
Yeah. It's nice here.
Um, I'm really just looking t-to leave here as fast as possible.
Eh, what, what? Leave Pottsfield?
Who wants to leave Pottsfield?!
- What?
- He wants to leave Pottsfield.
Oh, are we leaving already?
Let's leave immediately.
I'm just trying to get home.
- They're not supposed to be here.
- Maybe he's here to steal our crops.
To ruin our party.
Or take off our pumpkin shoes!
Uh, no, I, uh...
Now, hold on, everybody.
Let's not jump to any conclusions.
Whoa.
Enoch, what shall we do with them?
I-I'm done.
Now, let's see here, boys.
How did you end up in this little town of ours?
Well, we were trying to get home.
We came into town from the woods.
Uh, we saw your farms and your houses and thought,
"hey, here's a normal place with normal people."
And we both stepped on pumpkins.
Yeah, a-and then we heard the music from the barn, and,
well, uh...
h-how about we just leave?
Now, let me get this straight...
You come to our town,
you trample our crops,
you interrupt our private engagement,
and now you want to leave?
Uh...
Yes.
You'll never convict!
You have no proof!
This one's trying to escape!
Let me go!
I don't know these clowns!
Children, it saddens me that
you don't wish to stay here with us,
I simply have to punish you for your transgressions.
I told you this place was bad news.
So, by order of the Pottsfield chamber of commerce,
I find you guilty of trespassing,
destruction of property, disturbing the peace,
and murder.
Murder?
Oh, no, not murder.
But for those other crimes, I sentence you to...
a few hours of manual labor.
Wait. What? Really?
That's it?
♪ Among the fields of straw and stover ♪
♪ Clocked in 'till the work day is over ♪
♪ Time's a gentle stream, longer than it seems ♪
♪ Patient is the night ♪
♪ How I long to see her face now ♪
♪ Her starry, moonlit gaze now ♪
♪ I know she's never late, so anxiously I wait ♪
♪ Patient is the night ♪
Just a few hours of manual labor,
and we're almost done.
And then what are you gonna do...
just wander around? This way and that way?
Through the woods forevermore?
Uh, uh,
maybe we'll just stay here in Pottsfield.
It's nice here.
I don't know. I don't know.
Why do they even have you digging these holes?
Planting seeds or something.
Huh, maybe they're gonna bury you out here.
pfft
Hey! Buried treasure!
Whoa! Really?
See, Beatrice? What'd you find?
A skeleton!
We're digging our own...
Huh!
I-I-I was wrong. I was wrong all along.
I-I don't know how to get us home.
Use your little feet to pick our locks!
O-ho! Now you want my help?
I don't want your help.
Yes! I want your help!
- Beatrice, serio...
- Your time is up!
Aah!
Have the holes been dug?
Uh... Yeah.
Splendid! Well then..
But, no.
No?
Uh...
Psst!
Keep stalling.
Right.
Yeah, uh, you know,
we were digging, and there were too many rocks.
You guys don't like rocks, right?
- I don't think we do.
- I don't think so.
No, we don't like rocks.
See? So we were like,
"we should get rid of these rocks."
Well, that's a good idea.
Right? Yeah.
So, we were getting rid of the rocks and... huh?
Huh?
What? They left me.
So, what happened to the rocks?
Uh, the rocks...
Yeah, they... they were, um, you know...
they... they... they got in the way of all the...
well, the dirt, you know, and... W-Whoa! Ohh!
Welcome back, Larry!
Hey, he looks exactly the same.
What in the...
Whooooop! Ooh!
Yeah, Larry! Whoo!
Look at that guy go!
Edward, this one's for you!
They're all skeletons.
Thanks for digging up the life of the party.
What a wonderful harvest. And what about you?
You sure you want to leave?
Me? Yes?
Oh, well. You'll join us someday.
Uh...
Psst!
Why are you still here?
What do you mean? You guys left me!
- Oh.
- Come on.
Oh. Are they chasing us?
- Nope.
- No.
I-I thought you guys...
You're welcome.
Thank you.
I guess we're even now, huh?
You're not honor-bound to help us anymore.
huh, I wish.
But you weren't actually in any danger with those weirdos.
Oh, yeah!
Then you still have to help us get home.
I got it!
I wish Wirt Jr. had fingernails so he could play the guitar better.
So... Yeah, I'll bring you to Adelaide.
I mean, that's where I'm going anyway.
Why are you going to Adelaide's
I guess, in some ways,
I'm trying to get home, too.
That's vague. What does that mean?
I don't have to tell you anything.
Well, I sure hope
Adelaide is more helpful than that woodsman was.
I think his directions were...
not very good.